# **Marc Bucchieri**

Portland, OR | 781-258-8074 | bucchierimarc@gmail.com | www.upwork.com/fl/marcbucchieri | www.linkedin.com/in/marc-bucchieri-352b9877/

#### **SUMMARY**

Since graduating with a Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering from Tufts University I have grown my interpersonal and management skills through several years working in the education field. Most of my recent work involves web development for the non-profit White Mountain Science and Java instruction for KTByte.

My twin passions are helping people develop and discover themselves and designing creative solutions for human problems, often in the education and medical fields.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

November 2016 - Present

Full Stack Developer, White Mountain Science, Inc., Littleton NH

- Develop educational sites using Javascript, HTML5, JQuery, Google Cloud Functions, and multiple APIs including REST
- Assist with teacher professional development workshops and after school programs in K-12 classrooms
- Created Instructor Developer Corps program for seasonal employees to assist with product development and outreach
- Created bottom-up server configuration, Flask-based web app, and database tools on wmsinh.org

February 2020 - Present

#### **Java Instructor**, KTByte

- Teach beginner- and intermediate-level computer science classes.
- Keep classes engaging and intuitive for early learners.
- Code and explain solutions to programming challenges

January 2019 - Present

## Freelance Engineer, Self-Employed via Upwork

- Create a variety of full stack web development products to meet client needs, including React.js front end work.
- Produce structural CAD models and drawings for residential and industrial clients.
- Maintain professional-level competence with mechanical design and web development tools.

January 2019 - February 2020

### Mechanical Engineer, HKIdeation, Portland OR

- Design medical device accessories to solve surgical human factors challenges
- Use rapid prototyping to iterate over designs
- Recommend fabrication techniques based on design constraints and product type

November 2019 - March 2020

Adaptive Ski Instructor, Oregon Adaptive Sports, Bend OR

- Create life-changing experiences for clients with varying abilities
- Maintain professional-level ski instructor certifications
- Contribute to non-profit fundraising efforts and community-building

May 2016 - October 2019

Instructor, Northwest Outward Bound School, Redmond OR

- Maintain institutional technical skills to lead whitewater rafting, rock climbing, backpacking, and mountaineering courses in the Northwestern U.S.
- Endeavor to change students' lives through challenge and discovery on educational expeditions
- Extensive training and practice surrounding human skills; including leadership, communication, and thorough feedback with co-staff
- Experience driving large manual transmission vehicles and 15-passenger vans

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

December 2018 - March 2019

Adaptive Ski Volunteer, Oregon Adaptive Sports, Bend, OR

## **SKILLS**

**Full Stack Developer**: React/ Redux, Node.js HTML5, Javascript, JQuery, Git, Python, REST API, UI Design, C++, Java

Mechanical Engineer: Solidworks, Onshape, AutoCAD, Matlab, Labview, Microsoft Office

## **EDUCATION**

Class of 2016

Tufts University, Somerville MA
Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, 3.91 GPA
Tufts Mechanical Engineering Award
Jason H. & Eleanor H. Samuels Mechanical Engineering Prize